<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>The OpenFn Blog</title>
        <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog</link>
        <description>OpenFn/docs Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>fr</language>
        <copyright>Copyright © 2023 Open Function Group, LLC.</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenFn Lightning Beta]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2023/04/13/lightning-beta</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2023/04/13/lightning-beta</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It's been a wild year and we're excited to announce the next generation of]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's been a wild year and we're excited to announce the next generation of
OpenFn's digital public good for workflow automation, <strong>OpenFn Lightning ⚡</strong></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="weve-just-soft-launched-openfn-lightning-and-heres-what-you-should-know">We've just "soft launched" OpenFn Lightning and here's what you should know<a href="#weve-just-soft-launched-openfn-lightning-and-heres-what-you-should-know" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to We've just &quot;soft launched&quot; OpenFn Lightning and here's what you should know" title="Direct link to We've just &quot;soft launched&quot; OpenFn Lightning and here's what you should know">​</a></h2><p>Lightning represents our commitment to open source and the DPG community. It is
a fully open source web application designed for governments and NGOs who need a
flexible solution to <strong>integrate and connect <em>any</em> system</strong>. It reuses our
existing tried and tested technology whilst lowering the technical barrier to
building robust workflow automation solutions and integrations through a more
intuitive, user-friendly UI.</p><p><strong>Read more about Lightning on our
<a href="/fr/documentation/about-lightning">docs page</a>.</strong></p><div class="theme-admonition theme-admonition-info alert alert--info admonition_LlT9"><div class="admonitionHeading_tbUL"><span class="admonitionIcon_kALy"><svg viewBox="0 0 14 16"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M7 2.3c3.14 0 5.7 2.56 5.7 5.7s-2.56 5.7-5.7 5.7A5.71 5.71 0 0 1 1.3 8c0-3.14 2.56-5.7 5.7-5.7zM7 1C3.14 1 0 4.14 0 8s3.14 7 7 7 7-3.14 7-7-3.14-7-7-7zm1 3H6v5h2V4zm0 6H6v2h2v-2z"></path></svg></span>info</div><div class="admonitionContent_S0QG"><p>At the time of writing, Lightning is still in beta and has some rough edges. 95%
of OpenFn users are still building workflow solutions on the v1 (available at
<a href="https://www.openfn.org/signup" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">openfn.org</a>) but we'll be ready for a full
migration later this year.</p><p>It's free to use during the beta, but we'll soon be providing a paid,
enterprise-grade hosted service like you've become accustomed to on OpenFn.org.</p></div></div><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="register-for-an-account-and-share-your-feedback">Register for an account and share your feedback<a href="#register-for-an-account-and-share-your-feedback" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Register for an account and share your feedback" title="Direct link to Register for an account and share your feedback">​</a></h2><p>Register for a free account at
<a href="https://app.openfn.org/users/register" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">app.openfn.org</a>. Help us out by carrying
out our <a href="/fr/blog#take-10-minutes-to-carry-out-our-user-test">user test</a> (~10
minutes) and adding your questions and comments to the Lightning thread on our
<a href="https://community.openfn.org/t/the-lightning-beta/297" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">community forum</a>.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="take-10-minutes-to-carry-out-our-user-test">Take 10 minutes to carry out our user test<a href="#take-10-minutes-to-carry-out-our-user-test" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Take 10 minutes to carry out our user test" title="Direct link to Take 10 minutes to carry out our user test">​</a></h2><p>Get your thinking hat on! We need you to click around OpenFn Lightning and
figure out how it works.</p><p><strong> 1. Start recording your screen, and speak out loud as you work through tasks
2 and 3.</strong></p><p>Use <a href="https://www.loom.com/looms" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Loom</a> to more easily share your recording - you
can create an account for free.</p><p>As you record, make sure to tell us:</p><ul><li>What you see</li><li>What you're doing</li><li>What you're thinking</li><li>What you expect</li></ul><p>For example, start off by saying "I've just started recoding my screen, and now
I'm going to start the first task. (…) I've registered for an account and I've
just been taken to the workflow page. I can see …"</p><p><strong> 2. Register / Login on
<a href="https://app.openfn.org/users/register" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">app.openfn.org</a>.</strong></p><p>Take 2 minutes to click around the app and view all of the different pages. As
you click into them, tell us where your attention is drawn and what you think
each page might be for.</p><p><strong> 3. Using the <a href="/fr/documentation/build/lightning-quick-start">quick-start guide</a>,
figure out how OpenFn works and what you can do in the application.</strong></p><p>What are jobs, trigger and adaptors? How do you run a job? What is the input?</p><p><strong> 4. Now, in your own words, explain to someone how to build a workflow.</strong></p><p>What is a workflow and how do I build one?</p><p>Why is OpenFn useful? What might discourage you from using it?</p><p><strong> 5. Send the recording to our product manager Amber at <a href="mailto:amber@openfn.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">amber@openfn.org</a>.</strong></p><p><em>•Note: the recording will only be used internally. If you wish for it to be
deleted once viewed please state so in the email.</em></p><p>If you would rather give your feedback in person, or have questions around using
Lightning, please book office hours with our product manager Amber via the
following link: <a href="https://calendly.com/amber-openfn/30min" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://calendly.com/amber-openfn/30min</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenHumans (A Travelogue)]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2023/03/01/open-human</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2023/03/01/open-human</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I am in the wrong hemisphere.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am in the wrong hemisphere.</p><p>Six months ago, I joined OpenFn, intrigued by the mission to automate workflows
in critical, but often neglected, humanitarian processes. For personal reasons,
I didn’t really plan on being here long - but I thought I could help out for a
while.</p><p>"Hey," says CEO Taylor Downs, one winter’s morning. "Do you want to come to Cape
Town with us?"</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Bo-Kaap" src="/fr/assets/images/bo-kaap-8ef429926bd7946d17c16fa737c9efd8.webp" width="1462" height="1097" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>I am not well traveled - I’ve never left Europe, let alone stepped foot on
African soil. So I enthusiastically agree.</p><p>And I’m not the only one. Between us, we have traveled 40,000 miles to be in
District Six, Cape Town - from London, Dakar, Arusha, Riga, Nairobi. It has
taken us over 150 hours to get here.</p><p>Right now we are gathered around this table, in this hot little room, scribbling
our truths onto this oversized piece of paper. We are, in our own little way,
trying to make the world a better place.</p><p>Suddenly the fan stops, the lights go out, the projector goes dark.</p><p>Load shedding just struck.</p><p>But the conversation doesn’t even waver. Eyes briefly flick to the light
fixtures, but we remain focused on refining our mission, putting an edge on our
purpose, comparing visions on how, where and when we can make a difference.</p><p>We have traveled all this way to figure out how to best work together.</p><p>If we don’t get this right, we can’t achieve our mission. We are digital nomads,
spread throughout Europe, Africa and North America. We rarely meet in physical
space. Technology enables us to collaborate, but it brings its fair share of
challenges too.</p><p>"Sitting down all day is <em>dangerous</em>," says Taylor. "We have to make this
<em>count</em>."</p><p>It has taken weeks of preparation and worry to get here. I’ve been arranging
travel, visas, domestic stuff, vaccinations. Since covid broke out, for three
years now, my partner and I have worked from home, in the same small flat,
always together. I fight back tears as we kiss goodbye on the doorstep, and
start my long journey.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Obligatory team photo" src="/fr/assets/images/team-cape-point-2a14bec98c59366e708d659af5e8f830.webp" width="1024" height="768" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>It's an overnight flight. I do not sleep. I hit Cape Town tarmac at 7am,
scrabble for a data connection at 8am, collapse into Stu's car at 9am. I watch
the city, the townships, the shanty villages, the mountains; a new world drifts
silently past the window. The environment is beautiful, the poverty is
heartbreaking.</p><p>In Simon’s Town, as I shake hands with my colleagues for the first time, we
learn things about each other that months of video conferencing could never
reveal.</p><p>By the end of the first day I am already exhausted, overwhelmed, burned out from
adrenaline.</p><p>Over the weekend, we walk, we swim, we kick a football, we drive, we eat, we
immerse ourselves in penguins (did you know Cape town has penguins?).</p><p>At an artistic retreat in Scarborough, we sculpt from clay, eyes closed, hands
busy, minds focused. A safe space, our guide tells us nervously, unsure how to
break an ice that has suddenly formed in 30 degree heat.</p><p>It is at the same time austere and liberating, creative and claustrophobic,
individual and collective. We swap chairs and work on each other’s sculptures -
nervously, at first, unwilling to do harm, but soon embracing the opportunity to
co-imagine, to co-create.</p><p>In the end it is a joy from which, I think, we all emerged changed.</p><p>“It was a little too woo-woo for me”, says Taylor, tears still drying in his
eyes. It is the most reassuring thing I have heard in days.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Taylor, laughing in the face of danger" src="/fr/assets/images/taylor-baboons-44169681c781ecfe699ed852e88b1145.webp" width="1170" height="878" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Later, as the sun sets behind us, on a Cape Town beach, we share our stories.
Between us we barely have a single thing in common - be it language, religion,
education, gender, background, hobbies. But maybe, it emerges, there is one
thing - just one slender thread - which connects us after all: a determination
to fight inequality.</p><p>We are not righteous. We all know we can’t save the world. We are not in the
business of toppling regimes, redistributing wealth, healing the sick. We do not
bear torches.</p><p>But we do have a contribution to make. Automation is our thing. We believe that
we can improve critical business processes in the “developing world” - the
places that big tech doesn’t care about - by taking away tedium, building trust
and transparency, and reducing errors.</p><p>In the office, unfazed by power cuts, we explore working practices, discuss
cultural differences, deepen our respect.</p><p>We learn how to talk about and discuss our data integration technology -
something so abstract that often even highly technical people don’t get it. We
learn how our technology helps the people Silicon Valley overlooks. We share
stories, explore ideas, learn about ourselves and the business.</p><p>On the penultimate day, I find myself overwhelmed with grief. Soon we depart to
different corners of the world, vanish behind our screens. Yes, I miss my big
monitor, my safe space, my family, my drinks cabinet, my PlayStation, my wok.
But I know that this special, sacred shared time is ending - and later I will
miss the company of my colleagues more than the comforts of home.</p><p>Somewhere during this long pandemic, between fleeing an unsafe office and
thriving in isolation, I Iost something. I forgot something important, something
about connecting to people, something about society, the world, my place in it.</p><p>In Cape Town, and with the humans of Open Function, I found it once more.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="An OpenHuman at Camps Bay Beach" src="/fr/assets/images/joe-beach-8e78a45a1bdebed5920682ecf4de7bda.webp" width="674" height="899" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Data Integration to better safeguard the world’s wildlife]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2022/06/28/Data-Integration-to-better-safeguard-the-world’s-wildlife</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2022/06/28/Data-Integration-to-better-safeguard-the-world’s-wildlife</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Since 2020, the Wildlife Conservation Society (“WCS”) has leveraged the OpenFn Integration Toolkit to collect, clean, and integrate critical data for critical conservation programs targeting the world's largest wild places. WCS and its partners work at the frontline of conservation, and with support from OpenFn, they can automatically and seamlessly integrate and quickly analyse the masses of data collected across dozens of countries.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since 2020, the Wildlife Conservation Society (“WCS”) has leveraged the OpenFn Integration Toolkit to collect, clean, and integrate critical data for critical conservation programs targeting the world's largest wild places. WCS and its partners work at the frontline of conservation, and with support from OpenFn, they can automatically and seamlessly integrate and quickly analyse the masses of data collected across dozens of countries.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="wcs-saves-wildlife-and-wild-places-worldwide-through-science-conservation-action-and-collaborating-with-local-communities-and-indigenous-people">WCS saves wildlife and wild places worldwide through science, conservation action, and collaborating with local communities and indigenous people.<a href="#wcs-saves-wildlife-and-wild-places-worldwide-through-science-conservation-action-and-collaborating-with-local-communities-and-indigenous-people" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to WCS saves wildlife and wild places worldwide through science, conservation action, and collaborating with local communities and indigenous people." title="Direct link to WCS saves wildlife and wild places worldwide through science, conservation action, and collaborating with local communities and indigenous people.">​</a></h3><p>Climate change is happening right before our eyes. The <a href="https://www.un.org/sustainabledevelopment/blog/2019/05/nature-decline-unprecedented-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2019 Union Nations SDG Report</a> found that as many as one million animal and plant species are in danger of extinction. Ergo, this also puts the people who highly depend on them at great risk. The earth’s demolition statistics are alarming, with “greenhouse gas emissions <!-- -->[having]<!-- --> doubled, raising average global temperatures by at least 0.7 degrees Celsius.” Less than 25% of the world can still be considered “wilderness”, urging that we must mitigate and avert these disasters without hesitation. Wilderness areas act as critical buffers against climate change, and as time goes on, these areas are diminishing due to global warming, leaving us vulnerable to climate disasters.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="wcs-works-with-multiple-data-platforms-and-dozens-of-partners-worldwide-and-needs-an-integration-solution-to-enable-interoperability-and-scale">WCS works with multiple data platforms and dozens of partners worldwide and needs an integration solution to enable interoperability and scale.<a href="#wcs-works-with-multiple-data-platforms-and-dozens-of-partners-worldwide-and-needs-an-integration-solution-to-enable-interoperability-and-scale" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to WCS works with multiple data platforms and dozens of partners worldwide and needs an integration solution to enable interoperability and scale." title="Direct link to WCS works with multiple data platforms and dozens of partners worldwide and needs an integration solution to enable interoperability and scale.">​</a></h3><p>With projects in nearly 60 countries and across oceans, WCS aims to re-establish a world where wildlife and people thrive in healthy lands and seas. WCS partners work on the frontline of conservation, ranging from Indigenous and local communities to national and local governments. Using mobile survey tools like <a href="https://www.kobotoolbox.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KoBo Toolbox</a>, WCS field staff can complete and submit data collection forms to track the well-being of local communities they support, local governance, reforestation activities, natural resource use, and other conservation and social science research data. WCS sought out OpenFN to integrate its data collection sources with one database for centralised analysis of all this information.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="openfn-automates-data-pipelines-from-field-to-office-ensuring-wcs-decision-makers-and-researchers-can-access-timely-accurate-information">OpenFn automates data pipelines from field to office, ensuring WCS decision-makers and researchers can access timely, accurate information.<a href="#openfn-automates-data-pipelines-from-field-to-office-ensuring-wcs-decision-makers-and-researchers-can-access-timely-accurate-information" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to OpenFn automates data pipelines from field to office, ensuring WCS decision-makers and researchers can access timely, accurate information." title="Direct link to OpenFn automates data pipelines from field to office, ensuring WCS decision-makers and researchers can access timely, accurate information.">​</a></h3><p>WCS implemented OpenFn to automate a standardised data flow between numerous wild meat consumption surveys and an MSSQL database to enable cross-partner data sharing and critical data analysis for a <a href="https://newsroom.wcs.org/News-Releases/articleType/ArticleView/articleId/10598/New-45-million-initiative-seeks-to-curb-unsustainable-wildlife-hunting-conserve-biodiversity-and-improve-food-security.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">€45 million initiative</a>. The initiative aims to curb unsustainable wildlife hunting, conserve biodiversity and improve food security.</p><p>Since then, WCS has implemented OpenFn to support its partners from <a href="https://consosci.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Conservation Social Science Partnership</a> (“ConSoSci”). ConSoSci uses OpenFn to deploy and analyse research data collected in the field rapidly. One OpenFn solution auto-scans social science Kobo ToolBox surveys to then automatically:</p><ol><li>Build <a href="https://www.postgresql.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PostgreSQL</a> and <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/sql-server/sql-server-2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MSSQL</a> databases and</li><li>Integrate the databases, making the field data quickly available for analysis and eliminating multiple manual configurations and data integration steps typically handled by a software engineer.</li></ol><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://consosci.org/portals/0/ConSoSci%20Toolkit.png" alt="OpenFn integration" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>OpenFn’s solution saves ConSoSci partners time and money, enabling researchers to access reliable data from multiple sources more quickly and effectively. They can then analyse this information to help address critical gaps in social science capacity, implementation, and accessibility in conservation. </p><p>Thanks to the OpenFn Integration Toolkit, WCS has the digital infrastructure to efficiently scale its data collection, analysis, and sharing solutions to enhance interoperability across its programs and partners. OpenFn automatically syncs hundreds of records across dozens of WCS sites daily, enabling the WCS Conservation Technology Team to redirect its focus to its core work–empowering researchers working to mitigate continued environmental damage. WCS believes that “by discovering how to save nature, we can inspire the world to protect it”, and OpenFn is committed to helping conservation stakeholders automate this discovery process worldwide.</p><p>To explore WCS and ConSoSci OpenFn solutions, check out the open-source code on Github (github.com/OpenFn/consosci). Next up for WCS are integrations between Kobo ToolBox and Asana. Stay tuned for more!</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="call-to-action">Call to Action<a href="#call-to-action" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Call to Action" title="Direct link to Call to Action">​</a></h3><p>If you have questions about our WCS partnership or integration toolkit, head to <a href="https://community.openfn.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">community.openfn.org</a> to connect and talk to like-minded social-sector integrators and OpenFn staff. We hope to see you soon!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>case study</category>
            <category>WCS</category>
            <category>wildlife</category>
            <category>Kobo Toolbox</category>
            <category>PostgreSQL</category>
            <category>MSSQL</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Making the Case for Health Information Exchanges]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2021/10/20/the-case-for-health-information-exchange</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2021/10/20/the-case-for-health-information-exchange</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I attended the OpenHIE Academy Live Event last week and learned about the]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I attended the OpenHIE Academy Live Event last week and learned about the
function and application of the OpenHIE Architecture framework and its
components. What's a health information exchange, and what does it mean for
people in everyday terms?</p><p>A health information exchange allows for health data to be entered once and
reused across different systems by defining standards and communication
protocols that enable many systems to work with the same data.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://wiki.ohie.org/download/attachments/41943663/openimis%20hie%20arch.png?version=1&amp;modificationDate=1573566637897&amp;api=v2" alt="OpenHIE Framework" title="OpenHIE Framework" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We can imagine various real world use cases for implementing a health
information exchange architecture. My cousin Mariam’s experience with healthcare
in Conakry serves as an example. After visiting three clinics and hospitals in
Conakry, Mariam was diagnosed with kidney stones at the fourth one. All of the
data that was collected in the first three clinics were not accessible to her
doctor at the fourth one. At each clinic the same data was collected and doctors
relied on Mariam to provide her medical history. They asked about past visits,
previous diagnoses, prescriptions, lab results, etc. Her medical history was
spread across paper and electronic systems, in her home, at different
pharmacies, and in labs. Imagine how much faster she could have been diagnosed
and treated if her healthcare workers had access to a comprehensive view of her
medical history.</p><p>A health information exchange would mitigate these issues and allow data to be
stored in a single database. All authorized stakeholders would be able to access
and update this single health record and Mariam wouldn’t need to stress about
her paper prescription she lost from years ago. <strong>Patient data is only one piece
of the puzzle and other important health data such as information on facilities,
providers, and supplies can also be managed in the health information exchange
system.</strong></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="openfns-role">OpenFn's Role<a href="#openfns-role" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to OpenFn's Role" title="Direct link to OpenFn's Role">​</a></h3><p>Two key components of a health information exchange are <strong>interoperability and
data standards.</strong> The OpenFn Integration Toolkit is a tool for interoperability
solution design, implementation, and adherence to data standards in health
information exchange–key for organizations seeking to securely increase
interoperability across systems and partners, reduce costs, strengthen health
systems, and improve service delivery. Released this year, the Toolkit is a
digital global good that helps health and humanitarian organizations and
governments automate key processes and integrate critical information systems.
It was developed in partnership with 45+ social sector partners, incorporating
resources and learnings from dozens of implementations to deliver a suite of
open-source documentation, implementation tools, and a templates library that
fast-tracks interoperability and automation projects.</p><p>For more information visit the links below:</p><ul><li><a href="https://academy.ohie.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://academy.ohie.org/</a></li><li><a href="https://docs.openfn.org/documentation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://docs.openfn.org/documentation/</a></li></ul><p>— Aicha</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Platforms, Processes and Legitimate Freedom at the National Government Level]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2021/07/30/processes-and-open-source-as-choice</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2021/07/30/processes-and-open-source-as-choice</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In 2020, Robert MacTavish, a child protection specialist at UNICEF Primero lead,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 2020, Robert MacTavish, a child protection specialist at UNICEF Primero lead,
met with the team at OpenFn and laid out a massive challenge facing the Ministry
of Social Affairs, Veterans and Youth Rehabilitation in Cambodia. He explained
that there was no secure, stable, scalable way to share data between different
case management systems operated by the government and partner agencies. The
result, he went on, was not merely an increased administrative burden but
re-victimization. Children might have to recount their whole case history,
reliving their traumas time and time again in order to register and access each
critical support service they needed.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="UNICEF Cambodia (c) Daravatey Seng 2020" src="/fr/assets/images/unicef-cambodia-cc-daravatey-seng-76d5f43d94f888412e6253cff7b4459f.jpg" width="765" height="510" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="fast-forward">Fast forward...<a href="#fast-forward" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Fast forward..." title="Direct link to Fast forward...">​</a></h3><p>...to the spring of 2021 and child protection case data is now being securely
transmitted between systems as part of a fully automated, secure referral
workflow running through OpenFn.</p><blockquote><p>If you’re not familiar with OpenFn, it’s an integration platform and toolkit
that has been used in over 40 countries to automate business processes,
connect disparate systems, and facilitate secure, stable, scalable data
sharing. Learn more at <a href="https://www.openfn.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenFn.org</a></p></blockquote><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="a-success-for-the-ministry">A success for the Ministry<a href="#a-success-for-the-ministry" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to A success for the Ministry" title="Direct link to A success for the Ministry">​</a></h3><p>It’s a big success for the Ministry, for UNICEF, and partner NGO agencies using
Primero and OSCaR—the first two case management systems to be integrated. You
can read more about it in the
<a href="https://www.khmertimeskh.com/50814828/beefing-up-child-protection-case-management/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Khmer Times</a>,
the
<a href="https://www.unicef.org/cambodia/press-releases/interoperability-between-primero-and-oscar-goes-live" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">UNICEF press release</a>,
or
<a href="https://community.primero.org/t/interoperability-in-primero-with-openfn-is-changing-the-way-we-work/360" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Primero’s community forum</a>,
but here I want to focus on a slightly more nuanced learning that came from this
<a href="https://openfn.github.io/unicef-cambodia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">project</a> and Digital Square’s recent
investment in the OpenFn “Open Source Integration Toolkit”.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="implementations-arent-always-re-usable-but-platforms-and-processes-are">Implementations aren’t always re-usable, but platforms and processes ARE.<a href="#implementations-arent-always-re-usable-but-platforms-and-processes-are" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Implementations aren’t always re-usable, but platforms and processes ARE." title="Direct link to Implementations aren’t always re-usable, but platforms and processes ARE.">​</a></h3><p>We built OpenFn because we were frustrated by the amount of time and money that
was being spent rebuilding the digital infrastructure required for secure,
robust, long-lasting integrations. Each integration project may be completely
different in terms of <em>how</em> data is processed (i.e., the “business rules”) but
there are some basic requirements and best-practices that can serve as the
building blocks for successful interoperability across almost any set of
systems. That’s no surprise to us; it’s the fundamental premise of OpenFn.
What’s expanded dramatically through our work in Cambodia, however, is our
collection of <em><strong>reusable processes</strong></em>—how to approach integration long before
you open up a computer—that can now serve as a template for future projects.</p><p>One such process is the “Integration Checklist”, a non-technical checklist that
helps organizations bring together relevant stakeholders and define the value
and rules of an integration. This is no small thing. In the Primero post
mentioned above, Jan Panchalingam, also a Child Protection Specialist at UNICEF,
writes that implementing OpenFn is “changing the way they work”.</p><p>The “aha” moment for those involved in this project was that the artifacts
produced in an OpenFn implementation—actual
<a href="/fr/documentation/build/triggers">“triggers”</a> and
<a href="/fr/documentation/build/jobs">“jobs”</a> written with and for the Open Source
Integration Toolkit—publicly memorialize the data sharing agreements between
partners.</p><p>I want to stick with that for a moment: <strong>the implementation <em>is</em> the
agreement!</strong></p><div class="theme-admonition theme-admonition-success alert alert--success admonition_LlT9"><div class="admonitionHeading_tbUL"><span class="admonitionIcon_kALy"><svg viewBox="0 0 12 16"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M6.5 0C3.48 0 1 2.19 1 5c0 .92.55 2.25 1 3 1.34 2.25 1.78 2.78 2 4v1h5v-1c.22-1.22.66-1.75 2-4 .45-.75 1-2.08 1-3 0-2.81-2.48-5-5.5-5zm3.64 7.48c-.25.44-.47.8-.67 1.11-.86 1.41-1.25 2.06-1.45 3.23-.02.05-.02.11-.02.17H5c0-.06 0-.13-.02-.17-.2-1.17-.59-1.83-1.45-3.23-.2-.31-.42-.67-.67-1.11C2.44 6.78 2 5.65 2 5c0-2.2 2.02-4 4.5-4 1.22 0 2.36.42 3.22 1.19C10.55 2.94 11 3.94 11 5c0 .66-.44 1.78-.86 2.48zM4 14h5c-.23 1.14-1.3 2-2.5 2s-2.27-.86-2.5-2z"></path></svg></span>tip</div><div class="admonitionContent_S0QG"><p>By <strong>operationalizing a data sharing agreement</strong> through OpenFn, these
organizations now have machine-readable granularity, full revision history, and
proof-of-processing for their contract.</p></div></div><p>A huge portion of the work required to make the case management systems
interoperable was done on calls, walking through different referral flows and
privacy requirements and getting buy-in from various stakeholders and legal
entities. Now, the output of those crucial conversations are not just notes or a
signed MOU and careful task lists for system admins, they are a series of
scripts that are stored and actually enacted, faithfully, automatically, and
many times every day by the OpenFn platform–automating data exchange between
partner agencies.</p><p>By implementing OpenFn—defining the case referral process and the requirements
of the agreement in machine-readable levels of specificity—they’ve actually
removed huge amounts of ambiguity and helped standardize the data sharing
agreements between partner ministries/organizations.</p><p>And the reusability of these processes isn’t just theoretical. They are already
being applied in three other big UNICEF implementations as we speak. The next to
go live will be in Thailand.</p><p>UNICEF and the Thai Ministry of Public Health are working to enable social
protection caseworkers using the Primero app to access relevant patient medical
history securely, via OpenFn and a ministry-managed API gateway. By
foregrounding the checklist, and making sure all the stakeholders in these
sensitive data-sharing agreements are on board with the concept that this
implementation is a way of formalizing and enforcing data sharing agreements,
the teams have been able to move much more confidently through the initial
prototyping process. At OpenFn, we plan to continue to build out the open source
process documentation that goes alongside the software—making it easier for
folks everywhere to achieve durable interoperability and manifest their data
sharing agreements.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="one-more-thing-on-the-subject-of-open-source">One more thing. On the subject of open source.<a href="#one-more-thing-on-the-subject-of-open-source" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to One more thing. On the subject of open source." title="Direct link to One more thing. On the subject of open source.">​</a></h3><p><strong>Open source is about freedom of choice, not money.</strong></p><p>For the moment, in both Cambodia and Thailand, the implementations are running
on OpenFn.org—our proprietary cloud-hosted service—but in both cases they’re
already evaluating plans to migrate these implementations to make use of the
FOSS-only deployment pathway we provide in the Open Source Integration Toolkit.</p><p>I think that’s hugely important. A cloud-hosted service might be the best option
for a given ministry during prototype, pilot, scale-up, or even national-scale
deployments—oftentimes they’re less expensive and more secure—<b><i>but for
systems as important as these, it’s absolutely critical that they’re not locked
in.</i></b></p><p>Governments must be free to export that implementation and run it on completely
open source software that they can debug, on whatever servers they’d like, with
support from whatever vendors they choose.</p><p>This is what recent investment in the Open Source Integration Toolkit, from
Digital Square, the FCDO, DIAL, and our team here at OpenFn has made possible.
From software, to documentation, to process and implementation guides like those
mentioned above, the goal of the toolkit is to build up the integration
capability of the sector at large. Ultimately the toolkit will ensure that
OpenFn implementations aren’t forever reliant on a single company. It will
increase the substantive freedom of governments to make long-term plans and take
long-term ownership of their integration solutions, without having to re-code
the wheel.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="to-take-action">To take action<a href="#to-take-action" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to To take action" title="Direct link to To take action">​</a></h3><p>To join our community please sign up to our
<a href="https://community.openfn.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">community page </a>and feel free to contribute and
ask questions on the forum.</p><p>If your organization is thinking about interoperability and would like to learn
more about OpenFn’s platform or open-source offerings please contact
<a href="mailto:services@openfn.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">services@openfn.org</a> for a free consultation.</p><p>Also, be sure to stay tuned to our <a href="/fr/blog">blog</a>, or subscribe to our
<a href="http://eepurl.com/hcOw8H" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">newsletter</a> to stay up to date with all ICT4D
integration related news.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>deployment</category>
            <category>global goods</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Becoming a Digital Global Good, Open Access, and Thoughts on OpenFn’s Long-Term Sustainability]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2021/03/30/digital-global-good</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2021/03/30/digital-global-good</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Digital global goods]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://wiki.digitalsquare.io/index.php/What_are_Global_Goods" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Digital global goods</a>
are adaptable, interoperable, open source software or content designed to meet
the data and management needs of country health systems. Incredible software
tools like <a href="https://www.dimagi.com/commcare/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CommCare</a>, a mobile data
collection and service delivery platform, <a href="https://dhis2.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dhis2</a>, a health
management information system (HMIS) used in over 40 countries, and
<a href="https://openlmis.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenLMIS</a>, a popular logistics system, are digital
global goods. OpenFn is proud to now be officially joining them on this list.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Bridge as public good" src="/fr/assets/images/george-washington-bridge-fce1acf242f369da8d24608e3b1470b1.jpg" width="1920" height="1279" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-imperative-for-digital-global-goods">The imperative for digital global goods<a href="#the-imperative-for-digital-global-goods" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The imperative for digital global goods" title="Direct link to The imperative for digital global goods">​</a></h3><p>The story of digital global goods began in July 2018 when the Secretary General
of the United Nations convened a High-Level Panel on Digital Cooperation to
strengthen impact and better direct global efforts in the digital arena. What
motivated this panel’s formation was a growing awareness that as digital
technology reshapes economies and society, it is imperative that the
technologies deployed do not exacerbate global inequities, but instead seek to
address them.</p><p>Co-Chaired by Melinda Gates and Jack Ma, the panel’s
<a href="https://digitalcooperation.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/DigitalCooperation-report-web-FINAL-1.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">final report</a>
provided recommendations for how the international community could work together
to harness digital technologies for positive change. One of the key action items
that emerged in the report’s aftermath was a call for global investment into the
creation of <strong>digital public goods to help attain the sustainable development
goals. </strong>Specifically, availability and accessibility to digital public
goods—and the data they collect—was introduced as being essential to address
issues of digital inclusion for all regardless of location, race, gender,
religion or socioeconomic standing.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-open-source">What is open source?<a href="#what-is-open-source" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What is open source?" title="Direct link to What is open source?">​</a></h3><p>Not all open source projects are digital public goods, but all digital public
goods must be open source. Open source software is code that is publicly
accessible—anyone can see, modify, and distribute the code as they see fit. Many
governments and international NGOs prefer open source software because of
customization and data residency requirements. Since our founding in 2014 OpenFn
has been committed to open-source software development and the source code for
most of the products we’ve built is freely available on
<a href="https://github.com/OpenFn" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Github</a>.</p><p>Notably, even though open source software is “free” the cost of deploying it and
maintaining it carries costs that are sometimes comparable to commercial
software licenses.
<a href="https://digitalsquare.org/blog/2020/2/13/openness-and-value-in-the-digital-health-sector" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Digital Square </a>explains
this dynamic further: “The misconception of open source as ‘free’ may be better
understood through the Romance languages. Open source is
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gratis_versus_libre" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">libre, not gratis</a>: free as
in speech, not as in lunch. In the case of many low resource settings, this is
the right kind of free. The need for adaptability is balanced by the ability to
adapt a software.”</p><p>An example of a successful open source software project that is also classified
as a digital public good is <a href="https://openlmis.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenLMIS</a>. OpenLMIS is the
leading logistics system used to track health products across national supply
chains and while they credit their open source approach as being responsible for
their deployment success to date, they have also experienced challenges related
to their business model. Business model challenges force open source project
maintainers like OpenLMIS and OpenFn to explore different types of revenue
streams that ensure long term sustainability of the projects.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-openfns-business-model-will-enable-long-term-sustainability-of-its-open-source-project">How OpenFn’s business model will enable long term sustainability of its open source project<a href="#how-openfns-business-model-will-enable-long-term-sustainability-of-its-open-source-project" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to How OpenFn’s business model will enable long term sustainability of its open source project" title="Direct link to How OpenFn’s business model will enable long term sustainability of its open source project">​</a></h3><p>Historically, lacking grant funding and without outside investors, OpenFn
decided that the best way to continue delivering high-impact implementations and
keep a laser focus on the needs of real-world NGOs that we serve was to build a
licensed, closed-source software-as-a-service (SaaS) product offering (see
<a href="http://www.openfn.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">openfn.org</a>). This product is dependent on the huge
suite of open-source software that we continue to invest in for the good of the
larger community—“core”, “adaptors”, and almost all of the software we build is
open source—but by licensing our SaaS we’ve been able to create a steady stream
of revenue that is only dependent on real-world customers seeing and paying for
the value they get by using the product. Selling subscriptions to the OpenFn
platform has not only helped it grow into a strong, trusted, enterprise-grade
product, but it has bootstrapped our implementation arm, subsidized our “free
forever” enterprise tier, and funded the further development of our open source
tools.</p><p>Thanks to recent support from DIAL, DFID and Digital Square, OpenFn is now able
to invest more time and energy into our open-source tools—building new software
to compete with and complement more directly our licensed platform and working
to make the existing tools more accessible to a wider audience.The licensed
platform and our open source project have a symbiotic relationship with one
another. Open source innovation drives platform innovation and vice versa.
Crucially, both rely on each other.</p><p>With a more robust <a href="/fr/documentation/microservice/home">open source offering </a>and
a heavy investment in documentation, it will be easier than ever for
organizations to get up and running with OpenFn and then choose whether they
want to scale their solutions on the platform or deploy them on their own
infrastructure using nothing but free open source software (FOSS).</p><p>Some will still choose to use our hosted offering, and we’ll be encouraged to
further differentiate that offering through the value that it provides—<!-- -->_<!-- -->not
<!-- -->_<!-- -->merely by virtue of it being proprietary. In fact, we see a future in which
NGOs and governments may shift seamlessly between all of our tools. We’ve
developed them with exactly this in mind, ensuring zero lock-in despite the
varying licenses.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-does-this-mean-concretely">What does this mean, concretely?<a href="#what-does-this-mean-concretely" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What does this mean, concretely?" title="Direct link to What does this mean, concretely?">​</a></h3><p>In the past it was quite challenging to use OpenFn’s open source tools, and we
feel that they didn’t provide enough functionality, out-of-the-box, to our
users. It’s not surprising to find, then, that almost all of OpenFn’s users were
on the proprietary platform. Going forward our
<a href="/fr/documentation/deploy/options">open source integration toolkit</a>, including
OpenFn/devtools, OpenFn/core, OpenFn/engine, and OpenFn/microservice, will be
more robust, user friendly and accessible. This means that anyone, anywhere can
build integration and automation solutions more quickly and interoperability
solutions will be within reach to organizations with varying technical
capabilities.</p><div class="theme-admonition theme-admonition-caution alert alert--warning admonition_LlT9"><div class="admonitionHeading_tbUL"><span class="admonitionIcon_kALy"><svg viewBox="0 0 16 16"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M8.893 1.5c-.183-.31-.52-.5-.887-.5s-.703.19-.886.5L.138 13.499a.98.98 0 0 0 0 1.001c.193.31.53.501.886.501h13.964c.367 0 .704-.19.877-.5a1.03 1.03 0 0 0 .01-1.002L8.893 1.5zm.133 11.497H6.987v-2.003h2.039v2.003zm0-3.004H6.987V5.987h2.039v4.006z"></path></svg></span>Microservice and devtools are being replaced by Lightning</div><div class="admonitionContent_S0QG"><p>Please note that <a href="https://github.com/OpenFn/microservice" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenFn/microservice</a>
and <a href="https://github.com/OpenFn/devtools" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenFn/devtools</a> are being deprecated
and replaced by <a href="https://github.com/OpenFn/lightning" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenFn/Lightning</a>, When
lighting is released.</p></div></div><p>Versatility is a key component of our open source vision. We are constructing a
system that users can grow and mature with. While our enterprise platform might
be right for your organization today, 5 years from now, once your organization
has its own dedicated IT team and server infrastructure, local deployment via
microservice might make better sense. The good news is that OpenFn integration
<a href="/fr/documentation/portability">portability</a> will make these transitions easy. Your
integration will run just as well on your servers as ours.</p><p>As the diagram below demonstrates we envision two main pathways for OpenFn
integrations. The tech savvy project manager will configure their workflows via
our intuitive platform, while the power IT user will configure their workflows
from the command line. Regardless of the chosen approach, there is flexibility
to change paths whenever required.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Deployment Paths" src="/fr/assets/images/deployment_paths-679ee07e834c20ae413318af2885c208.png" width="1600" height="742" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Again, <em>concretely</em>, this means our users will have more and better options for
how they run their data integration solutions. While they might use
OpenFn/platform to build and test solutions, they could easily choose to run
those same solutions on their own servers via OpenFn/microservice. Visit
OpenFn’s <a href="/fr/documentation/deploy/options">Planning for Deployment</a> page to learn
more.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="open-source-is-about-more-than-code">Open source is about more than code<a href="#open-source-is-about-more-than-code" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Open source is about more than code" title="Direct link to Open source is about more than code">​</a></h3><p>An open source project is nothing without a strong community underpinning it.
Led by a steering committee of stakeholders that represent our different users,
we are activating a diverse community around our products that will help guide
and power their direction.</p><p>This community of “citizen integrators” (people familiar with processes and
data, but not software development—e.g., program analysts, clinic data managers,
operations leads) will provide their valuable and diverse points of view and
will be equipped to design and build robust solutions to automate processes and
integrate systems.</p><p>To join our community please sign up to our
<a href="https://community.openfn.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">community page </a>and feel free to contribute and
ask questions on the forum.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="if-youd-like-to-learn-more-about-this">If you’d like to learn more about this<a href="#if-youd-like-to-learn-more-about-this" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to If you’d like to learn more about this" title="Direct link to If you’d like to learn more about this">​</a></h3><p>If your organization is thinking about interoperability and would like to learn
more about OpenFn’s platform or open-source offerings please contact
<a href="mailto:services@openfn.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">services@openfn.org</a> for a free consultation.</p><p>Also, be sure to stay tuned to our <a href="/fr/blog">blog</a>, or subscribe to our
<a href="http://eepurl.com/hcOw8H" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">newsletter</a> to stay up to date with all ICT4D
integration related news.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>announcement</category>
            <category>global goods</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enabling Interoperability for Child Case Referrals in Cambodia]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2021/02/09/interoperability_for_case_referrals</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2021/02/09/interoperability_for_case_referrals</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Over the past 12 months, OpenFn and]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the past 12 months, <a href="https://openfn.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenFn</a> and
<a href="https://www.unicef.org/cambodia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">UNICEF Cambodia</a> have worked together to
enhance interoperability for the critical software tools Cambodian agencies rely
on to protect and respond to the needs of vulnerable children and women. Key
outcomes achieved so far via this partnership include the implementation of a
secure OpenFn project space with the automated data sharing workflows required
to allow for the Cambodian government and their partner NGO caseworkers to
communicate with one another seamlessly.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Cambodia School" src="/fr/assets/images/cambodia_school-b19e3c1b72ab519dc0a2e8fecebc3d8f.png" width="1526" height="1221" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Case management applications help social service providers coordinate critical
support activities for vulnerable children; ensuring that they can securely
connect with one another and automating the flow of data between themshare and
the launch of these integration features is especially important amidst an
increase in the rates of domestic and gender based violence linked to the
COVID-19 pandemic. Additionally, the secure workflows the automation
allows—critically, facilitating the complex referral process—brings the child
protection system in Cambodia one step closer to the collective dream of
providing holistic, compassionate care.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-key-partners">The Key Partners<a href="#the-key-partners" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Key Partners" title="Direct link to The Key Partners">​</a></h3><p>The Child Protection team at UNICEF Cambodia, working in concert with the
country’s Child Welfare Department of the Ministry of Social Affairs, Veterans
and Youth Rehabilitation (MoSVY) defined the scope of the interoperability
requirements and guided this program’s implementation. Because achieving
interoperability can be complex, OpenFn was brought into the consortium to offer
expert integration insights and to provide the digital infrastructure required
to enable the program’s goals.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-systems-integrated">The Systems Integrated<a href="#the-systems-integrated" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Systems Integrated" title="Direct link to The Systems Integrated">​</a></h3><p>The systems OpenFn integrated for the first phase of this project are
<a href="https://www.primero.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Primero</a> and <a href="https://oscarhq.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OSCaR</a>. Primero
is an open source software platform that helps social services, humanitarian and
development workers manage protection-related data, with modules that facilitate
case management, incident monitoring and family tracing and reunification. OSCaR
(Open Source Case-management and Record-keeping) is a case management software
system that is used by civil society organizations in Cambodia to manage cases
or children in residential care.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Primero OpenFn Oscar Diagram" src="/fr/assets/images/primero_oscar-164912ef651cecccb7b2e559986c3037.png" width="1534" height="694" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>First a definition: “Interoperability”, in this context, is the automated
ability of computer systems to work in concert with (sharing data and
collaborating on processes with) other systems. Defining interoperability is the
easy part; achieving it is another story. “In a complex, interagency project
like this, it’s true that the technologies in play often don’t ‘speak the same
language’, but neither do the partners,” writes Aleksa Krolls, OpenFn’s Head of
Services. “Our job is not only to facilitate the flow of data between systems,
but to facilitate the process by which our partners—human users—communicate
meaning across multiple agencies and people.”</p><p>In this example, OpenFn’s software is acting as the “translator” between the
OSCaR and Primero systems. OpenFn’s primary interoperability objective for this
first phase was to facilitate Cambodian government partners and local
non-governmental organizations in systematic registration and tracking of
children in Cambodia, including facilitating duplicate detection between systems
and enabling easy-to-use processes for updating beneficiary/client details.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-work-is-just-beginning">The work is just beginning<a href="#the-work-is-just-beginning" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The work is just beginning" title="Direct link to The work is just beginning">​</a></h3><p>OpenFn’s work with UNICEF Cambodia and the MoSVY doesn’t end here though. We are
now beginning the process of enabling further Primero interoperability with
software like ProGres v2, UNHCR’s institutional tool, as well as enabling
Primero-to-Primero implementations in the field. We’ll be sure to keep the
community updated as the project progresses.</p><p>Many of the best responses to the critical issues we face as a society emerge
from collaboration and interoperability enables collaboration in the digital
domain. Just as no single actor or organization can deliver all the services
required to protect vulnerable children and survivors of violence, no single
technology can be successful operating in isolation.</p><p>Case management automation allows for a social worker to spend more time being
there for the vulnerable populations they serve and less time copying and
pasting data between the applications they use. This partnership between OpenFn,
UNICEF Cambodia and the MoSVY means that fewer children will need to painfully
re-tell their traumas just to receive the help they need.</p><p>If your organization is in the health and humanitarian sector and is thinking
about automation and interoperability, contact <a href="mailto:services@openfn.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">services@openfn.org</a> for a free
consultation.</p><p><strong>About UNICEF Cambodia:</strong> UNICEF Cambodia’s mission is to promote the healthy
development of children, to defend their rights and help them fulfil their
potential, from early childhood to adolescence.</p><p><strong>About Cambodia’s Ministry of Social Affairs, Veterans and Youth Rehabilitation
(MoSVY):</strong> Cambodia’s MoSVY is a government agency with a broad mandate that
includes supporting the efforts of social workers across the country.</p><p><strong>About OpenFn Group:</strong> Open Function Group (“OFG”) helps health and
humanitarian interventions in 40+ countries achieve scale and improve service
delivery through automation, data integration, and interoperability solutions.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>case study</category>
            <category>UNICEF</category>
            <category>Primero</category>
            <category>OSCaR</category>
            <category>Cambodia</category>
            <category>case management</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Connecting Beneficiaries, Data, and SMS to Expand the Reach of Literacy Groups Across South Africa]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/07/27/nalibali-case-study</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/07/27/nalibali-case-study</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Nal’ibali is on a mission to change education across South Africa through its]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nal’ibali is on a mission to change education across South Africa through its
reading-for-enjoyment initiative, which promotes reading and writing in mother
tongue languages. To effectively monitor program activities and children reached
across the country, Nal’ibali needed to integrate multiple data platforms.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Nal’ibali" src="/fr/assets/images/nalibali-7d358eefdf214f4ed70965580119450a.jpg" width="1134" height="850" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="did-you-know-that-south-africas-education-system-ranks-as-one-of-the-worst-in-the-world">Did you know that South Africa's education system ranks as one of the worst in the world?<a href="#did-you-know-that-south-africas-education-system-ranks-as-one-of-the-worst-in-the-world" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Did you know that South Africa's education system ranks as one of the worst in the world?" title="Direct link to Did you know that South Africa's education system ranks as one of the worst in the world?">​</a></h3><p>The results of the Progress in International Reading Literacy Study 2016 showed
that 78% of Grade 4 learners in South Africa cannot read for meaning, which is
the basis of learning. Children who aren’t good readers at a primary school
level are on a trajectory of limited educational progress. Nal’ibali aims to
improve academic success by promoting reading and writing in mother tongue
languages, which is important in a country that has has 11 official languages.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="nalibali-uses-language-and-cultural-relevance-to-develop-literacy-in-a-nationwide-campaign">Nal'ibali uses language and cultural relevance to develop literacy in a nationwide campaign.<a href="#nalibali-uses-language-and-cultural-relevance-to-develop-literacy-in-a-nationwide-campaign" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Nal'ibali uses language and cultural relevance to develop literacy in a nationwide campaign." title="Direct link to Nal'ibali uses language and cultural relevance to develop literacy in a nationwide campaign.">​</a></h3><p><a href="https://www.nalibali.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nal’ibali</a> (isiXhosa for 'here's the story') is a
national reading-for-enjoyment initiative to use the power of stories, either
oral or written and in many different languages, to inspire children to want to
read and write. Since this campaign began in 2012, it has had a tremendous
impact across South Africa through: 11,132 reading clubs (5220 of which are
currently active), 159,191 participants, and 1,419,035 stories distributed.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="with-multiple-systems-and-programs-there-was-no-single-view-of-childrens-literacy-progress">With multiple systems and programs, there was no single-view of children's literacy progress.<a href="#with-multiple-systems-and-programs-there-was-no-single-view-of-childrens-literacy-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to With multiple systems and programs, there was no single-view of children's literacy progress." title="Direct link to With multiple systems and programs, there was no single-view of children's literacy progress.">​</a></h3><p>To manage its nationwide literacy campaign, Nal'ibali used a collection of
technology platforms for data collection, reporting, and program management.
Nal'ibali implemented Salesforce for enhanced data management. However,
Nal'ibali still needed to integrate its OpenDataKit (ODK) data collection tools
and online learning management system with Salesforce to track the entire
program journey and progress of a child beneficiary in one, single-view.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="openfn-integrates-online-and-offline-data-sources-so-that-nalibali-can-monitor-childrens-progress-across-all-literacy-programs">OpenFn integrates online and offline data sources so that Nal'ibali can monitor children's progress across <em>all</em> literacy programs.<a href="#openfn-integrates-online-and-offline-data-sources-so-that-nalibali-can-monitor-childrens-progress-across-all-literacy-programs" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to openfn-integrates-online-and-offline-data-sources-so-that-nalibali-can-monitor-childrens-progress-across-all-literacy-programs" title="Direct link to openfn-integrates-online-and-offline-data-sources-so-that-nalibali-can-monitor-childrens-progress-across-all-literacy-programs">​</a></h3><p>To integrate siloed data sources and introduce automated SMS to boost reader
engagement, Nal’ibali implemented OpenFn to:</p><ol><li>sync all data collection tools across programs and activities for single-view
monitoring,</li><li>integrate Salesforce with Everlytic SMS to support direct communication with
beneficiaries, and</li><li>enable live monitoring of its reach through a live, integrated map
visualization that tracks the locations of reading clubs</li></ol><p>These OpenFn-powered integrations save the Nal’ibali team several hours every
month on data management processes and activity reporting. The connected data
systems also ensure Nal'ibali M&amp;E staff can quickly and easily monitor reading
clubs across South Africa, and analyze which campaigns have been the most
effective.</p><p>As Nal’ibali continues to scale its programs and reach, it released a new online
learning site for its readers earlier this year. Check it out the new site at
<a href="https://www.nalibali.mobi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.nalibali.mobi</a>! To learn more about Nal'ibali's
impact and mission, also check out
<a href="https://www.nalibali.org/impact-reach" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">their main website</a>.</p><p><em>The photo above was originally posted on the
<a href="https://www.facebook.com/nalibaliSA/photos/a.327956507281170/3081938088549651" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nal'ibali Facebook page</a>.
It features children doing role play in order to practice conversation.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>case study</category>
            <category>education</category>
            <category>odk</category>
            <category>Salesforce</category>
            <category>SMS</category>
            <category>learning management system</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Keeping Track of Payments to Help Sinapis Scale Small, Growing Businesses in Africa]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/07/26/sinapis-case-study</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/07/26/sinapis-case-study</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Integration has saved Sinapis staff hundreds of manual hours and ensures that]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Integration has saved Sinapis staff hundreds of manual hours and ensures that
all payment information is always accurate up-to-date to help Sinapis to run
programs smoothly.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Sinapis" src="/fr/assets/images/sinapis-f6620ab59bff0f3b65c9fbf7f13b10ca.jpg" width="860" height="645" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="sinapis-is-accelerating-small-business-development-across-kenya-uganda-and-rwanda-with-their-innovative-training-program">Sinapis is accelerating small business development across Kenya, Uganda, and Rwanda with their innovative training program.<a href="#sinapis-is-accelerating-small-business-development-across-kenya-uganda-and-rwanda-with-their-innovative-training-program" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Sinapis is accelerating small business development across Kenya, Uganda, and Rwanda with their innovative training program." title="Direct link to Sinapis is accelerating small business development across Kenya, Uganda, and Rwanda with their innovative training program.">​</a></h3><p>Sinapis found that small and growing businesses (those with 5 to 250 employees)
account for up to
<a href="https://sinapis.org/job-creators-why-small-and-growing-businesses-are-essential-to-recovering-from-a-pandemic/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">67-80% of new job growth</a>
in their respective economies. To help scale the impact of these businesses in
their communities, Sinapis provides a range of programs to empower
entrepreneurs.</p><p><a href="https://sinapis.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sinapis</a> is a nonprofit organization that empowers
aspiring entrepreneurs with innovative ideas by providing training, mentoring,
consulting, and seed capital. Sinapis was one of the first organizations in
Africa to start a program that trained entrepreneurs, including programs on
developing business ideas, how to scale, and tools for accelerating growth.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="to-manage-its-programs-sinapis-uses-multiple-technologies-to-get-the-job-done">To manage its programs, Sinapis uses multiple technologies to get the job done.<a href="#to-manage-its-programs-sinapis-uses-multiple-technologies-to-get-the-job-done" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to To manage its programs, Sinapis uses multiple technologies to get the job done." title="Direct link to To manage its programs, Sinapis uses multiple technologies to get the job done.">​</a></h3><p>Sinapis provides a range of online and in-person professional development
programs, mentorship opportunities, and trainings for thousands of
entrepreneurs. Some programs offer elite training at affordable rates, and
others are freely available to those who apply. To manage its program portfolio,
Sinapis uses Salesforce to register entrepreneurs and track program activities.
For payments, Sinapis relies on <a href="https://kopokopo.co.ke/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kopo Kopo</a> to collect
M-Pesa and other mobile payment types from enrolled entrepreneurs. Kopo Kopo,
however, was not integrated with Salesforce, so Sinapis staff had no easy way to
track payments and outstanding balances.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="openfn-saves-sinapis-management-time-by-integrating-payments-data-for-real-time-account-monitoring">OpenFn saves Sinapis management time by integrating payments data for real-time account monitoring.<a href="#openfn-saves-sinapis-management-time-by-integrating-payments-data-for-real-time-account-monitoring" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to OpenFn saves Sinapis management time by integrating payments data for real-time account monitoring." title="Direct link to OpenFn saves Sinapis management time by integrating payments data for real-time account monitoring.">​</a></h3><p>When payments are made via Kopo Kopo, OpenFn...</p><ol><li>Automatically matches incoming payments with existing Sinapis accounts,</li><li>Logs new payments and updates payment status in Salesforce,</li><li>Updates account balances to help staff monitor outstanding balances and
overdue payments.</li></ol><p>This OpenFn-powered payment integration regularly saves Sinapis staff several
hours of manual data entry work and ensures that all payment information is
always accurate up-to-date. This helps Sinapis to run its programs more smoothly
and focus on its mission to train 10,000 entrepreneurs. In 2018 and 2019 alone,
Sinapis helped employ 4,863 people and impacted over 24,000 lives by creating
jobs for those in extreme poverty.</p><p>Check out Sinapis’s
<a href="https://sinapis.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/2018-19-Sinapis-Annual-Report-Digital-Version.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2018-2019 annual report</a>
to learn more about their impact.</p><p><em>The photo above was originally posted on the
<a href="http://www.the-star.co.ke/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Star.</a> It features female entrepreneurs in
Kenya undergoing Sinapis's finance training.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>case study</category>
            <category>M-Pesa</category>
            <category>Kopo Kopo</category>
            <category>Salesforce</category>
            <category>payments</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Better Sanitation for Low-Income Urban Families Using an Integrated Supply Chain System]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/07/13/x-runner-case-study</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/07/13/x-runner-case-study</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In 2017, x-runner implemented OpenFn to connect its existing systems and sync]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 2017, x-runner implemented OpenFn to connect its existing systems and sync
data in real-time to more effectively manage and monitor waste collection
activities. With this integrated service system, X-runner can deliver high
quality customer service and technical assistance to their customers, with no
time lag.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="X-Runner" src="/fr/assets/images/x-runner-ccce8b4baabec33e93ffe573098a235b.jpg" width="674" height="367" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="x-runner-is-providing-sanitation-solutions-for-better-health-in-informal-settlements-in-peru">X-Runner is providing sanitation solutions for better health in informal settlements in Peru.<a href="#x-runner-is-providing-sanitation-solutions-for-better-health-in-informal-settlements-in-peru" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to X-Runner is providing sanitation solutions for better health in informal settlements in Peru." title="Direct link to X-Runner is providing sanitation solutions for better health in informal settlements in Peru.">​</a></h3><p>Almost 10 million people in Peru, or 30% of the total population, do not have
access to proper sanitation due to increasing water scarcity and constant
population growth. For many, only poorly constructed sanitary facilities are
available, which endanger the health and safety of families as well as the
environment.</p><p><a href="http://xrunner-venture.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X-runner</a> is a social enterprise that provides a
reliable, safe, and sustainable sanitation service to low-income urban families
in Lima, Peru who are unable to afford toilets. They offer a complete sanitation
value chain by linking a hygienic and waterless toilet for at-home use with a
weekly service that removes and converts the human waste into compost.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="x-runner-used-multiple-technologies-to-manage-its-work">X-runner used multiple technologies to manage its work.<a href="#x-runner-used-multiple-technologies-to-manage-its-work" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to X-runner used multiple technologies to manage its work." title="Direct link to X-runner used multiple technologies to manage its work.">​</a></h3><p>X-runner managed its operations through paper forms, Excel spreadsheets,
OpenDataKit (ODK) Collect mobile app, and Google Drive. With so many offline and
online platforms, information was often scattered, making managing customers and
tracking customer feedback difficult and time-consuming.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="openfn-helped-x-runner-build-an-integrated-supply-chain-system">OpenFn helped X-runner build an integrated supply chain system.<a href="#openfn-helped-x-runner-build-an-integrated-supply-chain-system" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to OpenFn helped X-runner build an integrated supply chain system." title="Direct link to OpenFn helped X-runner build an integrated supply chain system.">​</a></h3><p>X-runner implemented OpenFn to connect its existing systems and sync data with a
new Salesforce database to more effectively manage and monitor waste collection
activities. With integrated systems the process now works as follows:</p><ul><li>X-runner service operators pick up waste containers, scan a NFC tag attached
to the container to pull up customer details, log service information via
ODKCollect.</li><li>OpenFn automatically syncs the customer data with Salesforce, updating
customer details and logging the waste collection activities recorded.</li></ul><p>X-runner management uses the Salesforce platform to monitor the waste collection
services and track customer issues. Salesforce reports help to easily identify
issues for X-runner staff to immediately address.</p><p>With this integrated service system, X-runner can deliver high quality customer
service and technical assistance to their customers, with no time lag.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>case study</category>
            <category>x-runner</category>
            <category>development</category>
            <category>healthcare</category>
            <category>ODK</category>
            <category>Salesforce</category>
            <category>WASH</category>
            <category>supply chain system</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tracking Real-Time Progress of HIV-Affected Communities in Haiti]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/07/08/caris-foundation-case-study</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/07/08/caris-foundation-case-study</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[OpenFn data integration has enabled the Caris Foundation to "work towards a]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenFn data integration has enabled the Caris Foundation to "work towards a
better experience for the patient, for the agent, and for external reporting."</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Caris" src="/fr/assets/images/carisfoundation-943d25209d26c37fe84accd26edc59a4.jpeg" width="1500" height="1000" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><em>This post was published by Taylor Downs, Head of Product, on
<a href="https://medium.com/@taylordowns2000/supporting-communities-affected-by-hiv-98eede455050" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The OpenFn Founder’s blog</a>
as “Supporting Communities Affected by HIV.” Some changes and updates have been
made.</em></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="who-is-the-caris-foundation-and-what-do-they-do">Who is the Caris Foundation and what do they do?<a href="#who-is-the-caris-foundation-and-what-do-they-do" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Who is the Caris Foundation and what do they do?" title="Direct link to Who is the Caris Foundation and what do they do?">​</a></h3><p>Supported by USAID, the <a href="http://www.carisfoundation.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Caris Foundation</a>
implemented the
<a href="http://www.carisfoundation.org/pediatric-hiv" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Impact Youth Program</a> throughout
Haiti to improve the health of Orphans and Vulnerable Children (OVC) infected
and affected by HIV/AIDS. The foundation began an HIV program in Haiti in 2007
to support the healthy development of children and families by tracking and
assisting the clinical follow-up of HIV positive and HIV vulnerable pregnant
women, mothers, and children.</p><p>In collaboration with the Ministry of Health, the National Laboratory of Public
Health (read more
<a href="https://www.fondation-merieux.org/en/news/the-ministry-of-public-health-and-population-launches-haitis-first-national-laboratory-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>
as well as other hospitals and organizations operating in Haiti, the Caris
Foundation currently supports 150 hospitals across all 10 provinces, including
support in hard-to-reach districts and remote islands.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="operating-across-7-regional-offices-caris-foundations-network-provides-coverage-to-over-95-of-the-haitian-population">Operating across 7 regional offices, Caris Foundation’s network provides coverage to over 95% of the Haitian population.<a href="#operating-across-7-regional-offices-caris-foundations-network-provides-coverage-to-over-95-of-the-haitian-population" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Operating across 7 regional offices, Caris Foundation’s network provides coverage to over 95% of the Haitian population." title="Direct link to Operating across 7 regional offices, Caris Foundation’s network provides coverage to over 95% of the Haitian population.">​</a></h3><p>As part of Caris Foundation’s health worker outreach program, community health
workers ("CHWs") complete daily home visits to children and pregnant women with
suspected lapses in clinical and drug adherence. During these visits, CHWs
provide vital services such as counseling for clinical adherence, nutrition
screening and distribution of essential health supplies like ARV medication,
albendazole, and chlorine for water treatment. These services support
beneficiaries to regularly attend medical appointments, adhere to drug treatment
regimens, receive appropriate lab tests, and seek treatment for new or worsening
health problems.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="disconnected-systems-created-week--and-months-long-reporting-lags">Disconnected systems created week- and months-long reporting lags.<a href="#disconnected-systems-created-week--and-months-long-reporting-lags" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Disconnected systems created week- and months-long reporting lags." title="Direct link to Disconnected systems created week- and months-long reporting lags.">​</a></h3><p>Caris implemented <a href="https://dimagi.com/commcare/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CommCare</a> to enable CHWs to
collect data offline via mobile phone when working in remote environments.
However, all data collected for analysis, such as beneficiary profiles, services
received, and follow-up visits, needed to be manually transcribed via paper
copies into the HIV Haiti MySQL database. This process would take a week (and up
to several months) to complete, and sometimes the data collected would never
make it to the database.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="openfn-data-integration-saves-caris-foundation-staff-thousands-of-hours-enabling-live-automated-reporting">OpenFn data integration saves Caris Foundation staff thousands of hours, enabling live, automated reporting.<a href="#openfn-data-integration-saves-caris-foundation-staff-thousands-of-hours-enabling-live-automated-reporting" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to OpenFn data integration saves Caris Foundation staff thousands of hours, enabling live, automated reporting." title="Direct link to OpenFn data integration saves Caris Foundation staff thousands of hours, enabling live, automated reporting.">​</a></h3><p>OpenFn automatically processes and uploads data from approximately 5000 HIV
visits every month. Once in the database, the Caris Foundation is able to track
the progress of mothers and children as services are delivered in the field.</p><p>To date, OpenFn has automatically cleaned and uploaded 100,000+ CommCare
submissions to the MySQL HIV database, saving Caris thousands of staff hours
previously spent on data entry and reporting processes. To quote Jenifer
Fleurant, IT Programmer at Caris Foundation, data integration has enabled the
organization to “work towards a better experience for the patient, for the
agent, and for external reporting.” Read our
<a href="https://medium.com/@taylordowns2000/system-champions-caris-foundations-jenifer-fleurant-af4a4496d1d2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">interview with Jennifer here</a>.</p><p><em>The photo above was originally posted on the Caris Foundation
<a href="http://www.carisfoundation.org/pediatric-hiv" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">site.</a></em></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>case study</category>
            <category>Caris Foundation</category>
            <category>healthcare</category>
            <category>MySQL</category>
            <category>CommCare</category>
            <category>automated reporting</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Survey Monitoring and Quicker Analysis for Program Improvement in India]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/07/01/KGVK-case-study</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/07/01/KGVK-case-study</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In the past, it took KGVK months to digitize and analyze survey data before]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the past, it took KGVK months to digitize and analyze survey data before
sharing reports with key staff. By 2019, using OpenFn, KGVK was able to monitor
data in near real-time and better serve the needs of its communities.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="kgvk" src="/fr/assets/images/kgvk.v2-743f6bd113428eb14be9fc38951c7b8b.png" width="844" height="404" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="kgvk-is-a-non-profit-organization-with-a-mission-to-improve-the-livelihood-of-jharkhand-villagers-in-india">KGVK is a non-profit organization with a mission to improve the livelihood of Jharkhand villagers in India.<a href="#kgvk-is-a-non-profit-organization-with-a-mission-to-improve-the-livelihood-of-jharkhand-villagers-in-india" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to KGVK is a non-profit organization with a mission to improve the livelihood of Jharkhand villagers in India." title="Direct link to KGVK is a non-profit organization with a mission to improve the livelihood of Jharkhand villagers in India.">​</a></h3><p>KGVK has developed an integrated approach to development called the
<a href="https://www.kgvk.org/tvm.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Total Village Management model (TVM)</a>. This
approach, adapted to the rural setting, focuses on different key areas: natural
resources management, education, renewable energy, livelihood, women’s
empowerment, capacity building, resource mobilisation, infrastructure
development, and health, nutrition, and sanitation.</p><p>As part of its TVM intervention, KGVK administers an in-depth household survey
to tens of thousands of beneficiaries around Jharkhand each year. This survey
allows KGVK to evaluate access to education, financial services, healthcare, and
agriculture across the villages.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="without-data-integration-it-took-kgvk-months-to-digitize-analyze-and-report-on-the-survey-data">Without data integration, it took KGVK months to digitize, analyze, and report on the survey data.<a href="#without-data-integration-it-took-kgvk-months-to-digitize-analyze-and-report-on-the-survey-data" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Without data integration, it took KGVK months to digitize, analyze, and report on the survey data." title="Direct link to Without data integration, it took KGVK months to digitize, analyze, and report on the survey data.">​</a></h3><p>Using OpenFn to configure a ODK-to-Salesforce integration, KGVK was able to
connect is mobile survey collection tool (ODK) with its M&amp;E database
(Salesforce). The real-time data flow enabled KGVK to build dynamic dashboards
to monitor the village surveys, ensuring faster analysis. With enhanced data
access, KGVK can more regularly evaluate and adjust its programs to better serve
the needs of the Jharkhand communities it serves.</p><p>The photo above was originally posted on the KGVK Achievements
<a href="https://www.kgvk.org/achievements.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">site</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>case study</category>
            <category>KGVK</category>
            <category>education</category>
            <category>healthcare</category>
            <category>development</category>
            <category>ODK</category>
            <category>Salesforce</category>
            <category>data monitoring</category>
            <category>automated reporting</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building an Integrated Data Warehouse to Track and Share Student Performance]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/07/01/african-school-of-excellence-case-study</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/07/01/african-school-of-excellence-case-study</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ASE had a diverse data portfolio spread across so many sources that couldn't]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>ASE had a diverse data portfolio spread across so many sources that couldn't
easily be analyzed. Open Function delivered a centralized, single-view solution
for monitoring students and sharing data across schools.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="ase" src="/fr/assets/images/ase-c4056f7dd3b59b9d0595cb8d6d03fc3b.jpg" width="1444" height="960" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="african-school-of-excellence-is-working-to-deliver-quality-affordable-education-in-south-africa">African School of Excellence is working to deliver quality, affordable education in South Africa.<a href="#african-school-of-excellence-is-working-to-deliver-quality-affordable-education-in-south-africa" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to African School of Excellence is working to deliver quality, affordable education in South Africa." title="Direct link to African School of Excellence is working to deliver quality, affordable education in South Africa.">​</a></h3><p>In South Africa, school funding and tuition costs often defer students from
reaching their full potential.
<a href="http://www.ase.org.za/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">African School of Excellence (ASE)</a> helps students
access affordable, world-class education by providing affordable world-class
education to everyone through the creation of a self-sustaining network of elite
independent secondary schools at a fraction of the cost.</p><p>ASE focuses their mission on three essential factors: world-class quality,
affordability, and scalability; They believe their students will succeed in
South Africa and internationally when provided attainable education. ASE seeks
to grow an even bigger network of schools throughout South Africa to provide the
tens of thousands of disadvantaged students with elite education.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ase-had-a-diverse-but-disconnected-data-portfolio">ASE had a diverse, but disconnected data portfolio.<a href="#ase-had-a-diverse-but-disconnected-data-portfolio" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to ASE had a diverse, but disconnected data portfolio." title="Direct link to ASE had a diverse, but disconnected data portfolio.">​</a></h3><p>ASE used Google, Khan Academy, EdAdmin, and a custom built survey app to track
student progress. The data set was rich, but diverse and spread across so many
sources, so it couldn't easily be analyzed.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="to-connect-the-data-sources-and-enable-easy-quick-analysis-open-function-group">To connect the data sources and enable easy, quick analysis, Open Function Group…<a href="#to-connect-the-data-sources-and-enable-easy-quick-analysis-open-function-group" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to To connect the data sources and enable easy, quick analysis, Open Function Group…" title="Direct link to To connect the data sources and enable easy, quick analysis, Open Function Group…">​</a></h3><ul><li>Built a data warehouse on PostgreSQL database to centrally capture data across
the organization,</li><li>Implemented OpenFn to integrate the existing siloed data sources,</li><li>Configured an analytics layer using Readash for real-time program monitoring,
and</li><li>Enabled data sharing across teachers, partners, and schools.</li></ul><p>By building an integrated data warehouse , OFG delivered a centralized,
single-view solution for monitoring students and sharing data across schools.
With OpenFn, ASE has access to student data like never before. To learn more
about OFG data warehouse solutions, see
<a href="https://www.openfn.org/solutions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Solutions</a> or
<a href="mailto://admin@openfn.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">contact our team</a>.</p><p>The photo above was originally posted on the Wikimedia
<a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:WikiAfrica_Schools_training_African_School_for_Excellence_(23).jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">site</a>
under "WikiAfrica Schools training Africa School of Excellence."</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>case study</category>
            <category>African School of Excellence</category>
            <category>education</category>
            <category>PostgreSQL</category>
            <category>Redash</category>
            <category>data warehouse</category>
            <category>automated reporting</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helping an Airport Soar: Synchronizing Asset Data Between the Tarmac and HQ]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/07/01/airport-case-study</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/07/01/airport-case-study</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[With real-time data syncs, OpenFn helps this airport ensure top-quality assets]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With real-time data syncs, OpenFn helps this airport ensure top-quality assets
and service for its workers and passengers. This integrated asset management
system saves time and money, and prevents errors by reducing manual, paper-based
data transfer between systems.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="airport" src="/fr/assets/images/airport-254fcef7c6955e66aabfce135b58df96.jpeg" width="1260" height="708" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="airports-are-complex-businesses-responsible-for-passengers-equipment-employees-and-safety">Airports are complex businesses, responsible for passengers, equipment, employees, and safety.<a href="#airports-are-complex-businesses-responsible-for-passengers-equipment-employees-and-safety" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Airports are complex businesses, responsible for passengers, equipment, employees, and safety." title="Direct link to Airports are complex businesses, responsible for passengers, equipment, employees, and safety.">​</a></h3><p>Airports all over the world face the challenge of ever-increasing passenger
capacity and airline demand. To meet this demand, they put core infrastructure
and safety (for both workers and passengers) at high regard, and must prioritize
rigorous asset management, repairs, and maintenance.</p><p>An international American airport that serves 18 million passengers and 180,000
aircraft operations annually manages an extensive network of assets, including
heavy machinery, across a large area with intermittent network coverage. With
OpenFn, an international airport has unleashed the power of
<a href="https://www.ibm.com/support/knowledgecenter/SSBLW8/com.ibm.mamc.doc/overview/c_prod_overview.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM Maximo EAM.</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="this-airport-was-using-multiple-technologies-to-get-the-job-done-and-had-no-way-to-sync-information-between-technologies-and-service-teams">This airport was using multiple technologies to get the job done, and had no way to sync information between technologies and service teams.<a href="#this-airport-was-using-multiple-technologies-to-get-the-job-done-and-had-no-way-to-sync-information-between-technologies-and-service-teams" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to This airport was using multiple technologies to get the job done, and had no way to sync information between technologies and service teams." title="Direct link to This airport was using multiple technologies to get the job done, and had no way to sync information between technologies and service teams.">​</a></h3><p>To comply with FAA requirements, the airport conducts regular walk-downs in
which field staff rigorously document each asset and flag and photograph
required repairs. The airport uses IBM Maximo EAM to manage assets and schedule
repairs at HQ and CommCare to capture asset and work order data offline on the
tarmac. The staff regularly follows a manual process to transfer data between
the two tools, which is a time-intensive task with high risk for human error. HQ
was also not able to access and analyze information collected in the field in
near real-time.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="openfn-integration-delivers-real-time-service-updates-to-the-airport-hq">OpenFn integration delivers real-time service updates to the Airport HQ.<a href="#openfn-integration-delivers-real-time-service-updates-to-the-airport-hq" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to OpenFn integration delivers real-time service updates to the Airport HQ." title="Direct link to OpenFn integration delivers real-time service updates to the Airport HQ.">​</a></h3><p>This integrated asset management system saves time and money, and prevents
errors by reducing manual, paper-based data transfer between systems. OpenFn
also enables the field and HQ teams to each use the tool that suits them best:</p><ul><li>On the tarmac, field staff use an intuitive, affordable mobile tool (CommCare)
to receive new maintenance orders from HQ, document assets, and report and
photograph required maintenance.</li><li>OpenFn automatically forwards updates on assets and required maintenance HQ
staff.</li><li>HQ staff then use a leading industry tool (IBM Maximo) to store asset data,
schedule maintenance, and perform performance analysis.</li></ul><p>With real-time data syncs, OpenFn helps this airport ensure top-quality assets
and service for its workers and passengers.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>case study</category>
            <category>airport</category>
            <category>CommCare</category>
            <category>development</category>
            <category>IBM Maximo</category>
            <category>automated reporting</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real-Time Disease Monitoring for SwissTPH]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/06/25/SwissTPH-case-study</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/06/25/SwissTPH-case-study</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[By integrating a CommCare mobile data collection app with a national DHIS2]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By integrating a CommCare mobile data collection app with a national DHIS2
reporting system for the ALMANACH health initiative, OpenFn provided SwissTPH
with an automated, real-time connection that enables live disease monitoring
in 2019.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="swissTPH" src="/fr/assets/images/swisstph1-a40422f3055ed82aabd6f9ad4e5d2a93.jpg" width="5312" height="2988" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="swisstph-a-world-leading-institute-in-global-health">SwissTPH: A world-leading institute in global health<a href="#swisstph-a-world-leading-institute-in-global-health" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to SwissTPH: A world-leading institute in global health" title="Direct link to SwissTPH: A world-leading institute in global health">​</a></h3><p>The diverse professionals working at <a href="https://www.swisstph.ch/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SwissTPH</a> all
have one common goal: to improve the health of people globally. In Nigeria,
SwissTPH is helping healthcare providers to better screen, diagnose, and treat
sick children through the
<a href="https://www.swisstph.ch/en/projects/project-detail/project-action/detail/project-controller/Projects/project/implementation-of-almanach-in-the-icrc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ALMANACH health initiative.</a>
To do so, they are actively researching how to improve both curative care and
the prevention of disease to ensure the best treatment possible.</p><p>SwissTPH is a global health institute focusing on infectious and
non-communicable diseases, health system, interventions, and environment. It
aims to improve population health, nationally and internationally, through a
better understanding of disease and healthcare systems.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="swisstph-had-no-way-to-monitor-the-diagnoses-and-treatments-of-sick-children-in-nigeria-in-real-time">SwissTPH had no way to monitor the diagnoses and treatments of sick children in Nigeria in real-time.<a href="#swisstph-had-no-way-to-monitor-the-diagnoses-and-treatments-of-sick-children-in-nigeria-in-real-time" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to SwissTPH had no way to monitor the diagnoses and treatments of sick children in Nigeria in real-time." title="Direct link to SwissTPH had no way to monitor the diagnoses and treatments of sick children in Nigeria in real-time.">​</a></h4><p>To analyze disease patterns across health facilities, SwissTPH researchers would
have to wait days until staff members exported, cleaned, and uploaded the
diagnoses data collected to DHIS2—a time-consuming data process, prone to human
error.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="openfn-helps-to-bridge-the-time-gap-between-data-collection-and-analysis">OpenFn helps to bridge the time gap between data collection and analysis.<a href="#openfn-helps-to-bridge-the-time-gap-between-data-collection-and-analysis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to OpenFn helps to bridge the time gap between data collection and analysis." title="Direct link to OpenFn helps to bridge the time gap between data collection and analysis.">​</a></h4><p>OpenFn eliminates time lags, saving SwissTPH money and time and sending critical
patient information where and when it is needed, faster. By integrating a
CommCare mobile data collection app with a national DHIS2 reporting system for
the ALMANACH health initiative, OpenFn has provided SwissTPH with an automated,
real-time connection that enables live disease monitoring.</p><p>Every day the OpenFn automated reporting solution delivers 300 beneficiary case
updates and logs events with 100 individual “data elements” in DHIS2. The
solution runs on Switzerland-based cloud servers to ensure compliance with
SwissTPH’s data residency concerns.</p><p><em>The photo above was originally posted on the SwissTPH News
<a href="https://www.swisstph.ch/de/swiss-tph-news/news-detail-d/news/improving-health-of-children-in-nigeria/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">site</a>.
The Almanach tablet-based decision support tool supports health workers in
diagnosing and treating sick children. OpenFn integrates this data with DHIS2
for real-time reporting.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>case study</category>
            <category>SwissTPH</category>
            <category>healthcare</category>
            <category>CommCare</category>
            <category>DHIS2</category>
            <category>data monitoring</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Automating Real-Time Census Monitoring and Data Cleaning for iKapaData]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/06/10/iKapaData-Case-Study</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/06/10/iKapaData-Case-Study</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In 2017, OpenFn has saved the iKapaData team valuable time typically spent on]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 2017, OpenFn has saved the iKapaData team valuable time typically spent on
manual data entry and cleaning processes.The real-time connection has enabled
live data monitoring for the team as iKapaData survey enumerators were
conducting the survey.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="ikapa" src="/fr/assets/images/ikapa2-f44d61a34f5b5203b90dc9abd2b576ba.jpg" width="1024" height="768" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ikapadatas-essential-work-in-south-africa">iKapaData's essential work in South Africa<a href="#ikapadatas-essential-work-in-south-africa" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to iKapaData's essential work in South Africa" title="Direct link to iKapaData's essential work in South Africa">​</a></h3><p>The census plays an important role in public administration by creating a
compiled, numerical profile of South Africa. Enumerators are taught the local
language and local customs in order to effectively achieve information from all
households. This dataset is used as a benchmark in research and analysis for the
public administration to determine policy decisions, budget decisions, and more.
OpenFn enabled a system for iKapaData to ensure this delivery of accurate and
timely information for the census.</p><p><a href="http://ikapadata.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">iKapaData</a> is a survey research and data science company
with an aim to make data accessible, tangible, and actionable. For a census in
South Africa in 2017, they were collecting household data using
<a href="https://www.surveycto.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SurveyCTO.</a> Each enumerator participating in the
fieldwork was equipped with a tablet and an external GPS device for data
collection.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ikapadata-had-no-way-to-actively-monitor-data-collection-activities-on-the-ground">iKapaData had no way to actively monitor data collection activities on the ground.<a href="#ikapadata-had-no-way-to-actively-monitor-data-collection-activities-on-the-ground" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to iKapaData had no way to actively monitor data collection activities on the ground." title="Direct link to iKapaData had no way to actively monitor data collection activities on the ground.">​</a></h4><p>As enumerators collected the census data, iKapaData wanted to analyze that
dataset using two reporting applications, <a href="https://carto.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Carto</a> and
<a href="https://www.zoho.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Zoho</a> – each with its own data model and required
formats. To upload the data into the two reporting systems, iKapaData would have
to rely on time-intensive manual data migration, and there was no easy way to
actively monitor the census data collection.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="real-time-data-integration-enabled-live-survey-monitoring-and-quicker-analysis">Real-time data integration enabled live survey monitoring and quicker analysis.<a href="#real-time-data-integration-enabled-live-survey-monitoring-and-quicker-analysis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Real-time data integration enabled live survey monitoring and quicker analysis." title="Direct link to Real-time data integration enabled live survey monitoring and quicker analysis.">​</a></h4><p>OpenFn automation saved the iKapaData team valuable time typically spent on
manual data entry and cleaning processes. Using OpenFn, iKapaData set up
automated data cleaning and reporting pipelines that:</p><ul><li>Automatically extracted data from SurveyCTO on a scheduled basis,</li><li>Transformed data to the appropriate reporting formats for data and geo-spatial
analysis and,</li><li>Uploaded key results to Zoho Analytics, while also adding locations to a map
on CartoDB to display the locations already visited by enumerators.</li></ul><p>The real-time connection enabled live data monitoring for the team as iKapaData
survey enumerators were conducting the survey.</p><p>Learn more about OpenFn and SurveyCTO integrations
<a href="https://www.surveycto.com/blog/connecting-with-openfn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>case study</category>
            <category>iKapaData</category>
            <category>SurveyCTO</category>
            <category>Zoho</category>
            <category>Carto</category>
            <category>data monitoring</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enabling Scale at myAgro, 6 Years Later]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/06/09/enabling-scale-at-myagro</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/06/09/enabling-scale-at-myagro</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[OpenFn is helping small-scale farmers break the cycle of poverty with an]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenFn is helping small-scale farmers break the cycle of poverty with an
automated savings &amp; supply chain system. Small-scale farmers are feeding the
world, but a majority of them are in an endless cycle of poverty and lack access
to traditional banks and financing. In this post, we highlight our partner
myAgro, an organization leveraging OpenFn automation to help scale its programs
towards its goal of serving 1 million farmers in 2025.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="myAgro" src="/fr/assets/images/myAgro1-2ca3797d21345de19cb745f98fe8e3d3.JPG" width="700" height="467" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="heres-the-overview">Here's the overview.<a href="#heres-the-overview" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Here's the overview." title="Direct link to Here's the overview.">​</a></h3><p><a href="https://www.myagro.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">myAgro</a> has pioneered an innovative bankless savings
plan that allows thousands of farmers to finance themselves and invest their
money in high-quality seeds, fertilizer, tools, and training. OpenFn automates
myAgro’s mobile layaway platform, powering a system where farmers can
incrementally pay for agricultural inputs by purchasing savings vouchers in
local stores—making deposits via SMS. myAgro holds those layaway payments until
planting time, when bulk purchases of seeds, fertilizers, and tools are
delivered to the farmers based on individualized plans.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-myagro">What is myAgro?<a href="#what-is-myagro" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What is myAgro?" title="Direct link to What is myAgro?">​</a></h3><p>myAgro helps thousands of farmers in Senegal and Mali save money for seed and
fertilizer using what they already have—their mobile phone. With a mission to
move small-scale farmers out of poverty, myAgro leveraged OpenFn to develop a
mobile layaway platform that connects their Telerivet SMS-based savings deposit
system, Salesforce farmer tracking &amp; supply chain system, and CommCare
barcode-scanning mobile app.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="myagro" src="/fr/assets/images/farmers-9a9c1f15f22d45cc32159c1e47bd5a0e.jpg" width="4234" height="1468" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="using-excel-and-paper-to-manage-thousands-of-farmer-transactions">Using Excel and paper to manage thousands of farmer transactions.<a href="#using-excel-and-paper-to-manage-thousands-of-farmer-transactions" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Using Excel and paper to manage thousands of farmer transactions." title="Direct link to Using Excel and paper to manage thousands of farmer transactions.">​</a></h3><p>In 2014, myAgro utilized <a href="https://telerivet.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Telerivet</a>, an instant SMS and
voice platform, to capture farmer savings deposits, and paper to track voucher
shipments. They would then regularly export the SMS data to an Excel
spreadsheet, and manually match savings deposits against a database of vouchers
before allocating credit to a farmer’s account and sending a confirmation SMS.
Staff spent 1-2 hours per day (or 261+ hours per year) on this data
reconciliation process, which had high potential for human error.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="where-openfn-comes-in">Where OpenFn comes in...<a href="#where-openfn-comes-in" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Where OpenFn comes in..." title="Direct link to Where OpenFn comes in...">​</a></h3><p>OpenFn moved this entire manual process over to the cloud, automating the
savings deposit system and connecting a CommCare barcode-scanning mobile app for
real-time farmer order management and inventory tracking. By integrating
Telerivet and Salesforce, myAgro no longer has to rely on data entries and
uploads that would take 1-2 hours each day.</p><p>OpenFn now processes all SMS messages automatically, builds trust by providing
instant confirmation to farmers, and eliminates the chance of human error in
savings allocations. OpenFn helped myAgro transition from managing rows and
columns of data in an Excel spreadsheet to an automated savings and inventory
tracking system that enables real-time program monitoring.</p><ul><li>In 2014, myAgro serviced 14,000 farmers across 200 villages in Senegal and
Mali.</li><li>With the help of OpenFn, myAgro worked with 120,000 farmers in 2019, and plans
to scale towards its goal of reaching <code>1 million farmers</code> by 2025.</li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="myagro" src="/fr/assets/images/myagrograph-bf14565eddffbd2a30d7d8eede4b0f16.jpg" width="1080" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Read more about myAgro’s mission <a href="https://www.myagro.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>, and stay tuned
as myAgro continues to scale its OpenFn implementation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>case study</category>
            <category>myAgro</category>
            <category>agriculture</category>
            <category>CommCare</category>
            <category>Salesforce</category>
            <category>Telerivet</category>
            <category>data monitoring</category>
            <category>SMS</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building Integrated Systems That Just Work]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/06/04/Building-Integrated-Systems-That-Just-Work</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/06/04/Building-Integrated-Systems-That-Just-Work</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[OpenFn provides the "Rosetta Stone" for your technologies and integrates any]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenFn provides the "Rosetta Stone" for your technologies and integrates any
app.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="roads" src="/fr/assets/images/roads-a51d2c353c69c0dcc7bc00457e4332b3.jpg" width="3648" height="3648" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><em>This article was originally posted by Taylor Downs, Head of Product, on
<a href="https://medium.com/@taylordowns2000" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The OpenFn Founder's blog</a> as "Making
technology work better in the social sector."</em></p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="were-building-a-tool-that-will-make-integrating-critical-social-impact-technologies-trivial">We're building a tool that will make integrating critical social-impact technologies trivial.<a href="#were-building-a-tool-that-will-make-integrating-critical-social-impact-technologies-trivial" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to We're building a tool that will make integrating critical social-impact technologies trivial." title="Direct link to We're building a tool that will make integrating critical social-impact technologies trivial.">​</a></h4><p>The words “integrating” and “trivial” are not often written in the same sentence
— and for good reason! Non-technical readers click away when they read the
former, while developers see the latter and think it’s nonsense! (i.e.,
Integration is NEVER trivial.) This doesn’t leave a lot of you left here on
sentence number 5. Thanks for sticking it out, and let me reward your patience
by explaining why this is such a big deal and what we need from you to make it
happen.</p><p>By leveraging technology, we can make social programs more effective. Bigger,
better, more complete solutions to issues of poverty, public health, and human
rights are not only possible, but seem to be right on our doorstep thanks to
tremendous advances in information technology in the last 25 years. Thousands of
tools have been developed to address all sorts of needs across international
development. While the tools and use-cases vary tremendously, there’s always one
ugly, expensive, technically complex constant lurking in the background.</p><p>(Enter “integration” stage left.)</p><p>Just as “no man is an island”, no single piece of technology can stand alone. We
rely on integrations every day. Many applications are so tightly integrated that
we hardly notice. Gmail and Google Contacts almost behave like a single app. If
you’re lucky, Gmail and your calendar are also integrated. If you sync a folder
on your computer to Dropbox, there’s a nifty integration between your local
operating system and Dropbox.com. All of these integrations save precious time —
they cut out a tedious manual step like uploading a copy of each photo you save
on your computer to a website.</p><p>Now imagine running a pediatric HIV clinic in Kenya. Beyond email, a calendar,
and Dropbox, you rely on a fingerprint scanner to to quickly access patient IDs,
a smart-phone based data collection app for new patient intake during home
visits, an electronic medical record system to manage patient data securely, and
an automated SsocMS service to notify workers and patients of upcoming visits.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="we-should-take-a-moment-to-be-thankful-for-the-progress-weve-made-in-ict4d-its-amazing-that-these-technologies-exist-they-save-time-money-and-lives">We should take a moment to be thankful for the progress we’ve made in “ICT4D”. It’s amazing that these technologies exist. They save time, money, and lives.<a href="#we-should-take-a-moment-to-be-thankful-for-the-progress-weve-made-in-ict4d-its-amazing-that-these-technologies-exist-they-save-time-money-and-lives" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to We should take a moment to be thankful for the progress we’ve made in “ICT4D”. It’s amazing that these technologies exist. They save time, money, and lives." title="Direct link to We should take a moment to be thankful for the progress we’ve made in “ICT4D”. It’s amazing that these technologies exist. They save time, money, and lives.">​</a></h4><p>The problem is that, for lack of a better metaphor, these technologies all speak
different languages. You can ask users to download data from one, make sense of
it, and then upload it to another, but that’s a slow, expensive, and error-prone
task. (Not to mention the non-negligible fact that it’s horribly boring.) To get
the tos working together automatically you’re talking tens of thousands of
dollars, and the integration you’re left with isn’t re-usable once your needs
change. What’s worse is that every time a new technology is implemented within
an organization, consultants and developers must struggle anew to integrate it
with existing systems because there’s seldom the budget or foresight required to
build a truly flexible and future-proof integration. This is the issue we’re
tackling, head on.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="openfn-is-a-rosetta-stone-that-makes-automating-the-constant-flow-of-crucial-information-from-one-system-to-another-as-easy-as-point-and-click">OpenFn is a “Rosetta Stone” that makes automating the constant flow of crucial information from one system to another as easy as point-and-click.<a href="#openfn-is-a-rosetta-stone-that-makes-automating-the-constant-flow-of-crucial-information-from-one-system-to-another-as-easy-as-point-and-click" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to OpenFn is a “Rosetta Stone” that makes automating the constant flow of crucial information from one system to another as easy as point-and-click." title="Direct link to OpenFn is a “Rosetta Stone” that makes automating the constant flow of crucial information from one system to another as easy as point-and-click.">​</a></h4><p>Google.org called OpenFn’s attempt to provide easy and technology agnostic data
integration “the holy grail.” Stu, our own chief engineer had the same notion.
After some hard work, it seems that the platform may really be that powerful,
but also far more attainable. Here’s how we do it:</p><p>We use (1) a universal standard for data storage, (2) standard information about
what kinds of data are expected from “source applications” and “destination
applications”, and (3) a user-friendly interface to generate “jobs”—sometimes
called “automation scripts” or instructions for how to process data.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="a-job-might-be-to-create-a-new-patient-record-when-fingerprints-are-scanned-once-a-job-is-created-it-can-simply-be-switched-on-to-run-in-the-background-while-the-human-beings-at-your-organization-focus-on-much-more-important-and-interesting-things">A job might be to create a new patient record when fingerprints are scanned. Once a job is created, it can simply be “switched on” to run in the background while the human beings at your organization focus on much more important (and interesting!) things.<a href="#a-job-might-be-to-create-a-new-patient-record-when-fingerprints-are-scanned-once-a-job-is-created-it-can-simply-be-switched-on-to-run-in-the-background-while-the-human-beings-at-your-organization-focus-on-much-more-important-and-interesting-things" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to A job might be to create a new patient record when fingerprints are scanned. Once a job is created, it can simply be “switched on” to run in the background while the human beings at your organization focus on much more important (and interesting!) things." title="Direct link to A job might be to create a new patient record when fingerprints are scanned. Once a job is created, it can simply be “switched on” to run in the background while the human beings at your organization focus on much more important (and interesting!) things.">​</a></h4><p>For those of you who work in technology, the power of this strategy (namely,
using a universal standard) should be apparent. To integrate a new application,
a small adapter that translates data to JSON and provides a JSON-schema for your
database is all that’s required. Once one API connection to OpenFn is
established, <strong><em>your technology is instantly connected to every other technology
connected to OpenFn–and OpenFn can connect any application.</em></strong> It will start to
snowball quickly, allowing data to flow instantly between hundreds of crucial
applications, and each developer will only ever need to maintain a single
connection.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="apps" src="/fr/assets/images/apps-49baedba1e9bb9bdfc57016d05c8c453.png" width="1036" height="582" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Dozens of organizations worldwide use OpenFn to scale their interventions by
automating key processes and information flows. OpenFn solutions deliver
critical information, faster and unlock resources for organizations by
eliminating manual, time-intensive tasks. OpenFn connects any app–including
common ICT4D tools like DHIS2, CommCare, Kobo Toolbox, and Salesforce, as well
as databases, custom applications, and legacy systems. Drop us a note if you’re
thinking about how to connect tools at your organization, or if you’re a
developer and wondering how to get your product connected to other essential
tools in international development.</p><p>In the end, we’re talking about making it orders of magnitude faster and
significantly less expensive to integrate key technologies. By automating the
flow of data in social impact organizations we eliminate human error and reduce
lag time—this means better information in the hands of decision makers, faster.
All this leads to one thing: bigger, better, and more complete solutions to some
of the world's biggest problems.</p><p>If you’d just like some more information about OpenFn and how we help leading
impact-first organizations scale their interventions, head over to
<a href="https://www.openfn.org/solutions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Solution Overviews - OpenFn.</a> To get all the
latest OpenFn updates, like us on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/openfn" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a>
and follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/openfn" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>tips</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Technology Is Not The Answer, but It Should Not Be The Problem]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/06/04/Technology-Isnt-The-Answer</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/06/04/Technology-Isnt-The-Answer</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[OpenFn’s first objective is to knock down the technical hurdles so organizations]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenFn’s first objective is to knock down the technical hurdles so organizations
can focus on the important contextual stuff.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="tech1" src="/fr/assets/images/technology1-b08e3bc22a1ed2a711be3a572d34de2f.jpg" width="1024" height="603" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><em>This article was originally posted by Taylor Downs, Head of Product, on
<a href="https://medium.com/@taylordowns2000" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The OpenFn Founder's blog</a> as "Technology
isn't the answer, but it shouldn't be the problem."</em></p><p>March 23, 2015 — Salesforce Foundation originally published
<a href="https://www.salesforce.org/technology-isnt-answer-shouldnt-problem/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this blog post.</a></p><p>Three out of four IT implementations fail. While this is an accepted rate in the
corporate world where CEOs are accustomed to doubling down, conflicting
pressures and tighter budgets in the social-impact space push the chance of
failure even higher. Without good data, decision makers from the field to the
boardroom are hamstrung. Technology alone is never going to solve social
problems, but the inability to get it right has and will continue to sink
promising development programs. We built <a href="http://www.openfn.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">openfn.org</a> to
address this problem.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="heres-the-context">Here's the context.<a href="#heres-the-context" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Here's the context." title="Direct link to Here's the context.">​</a></h3><p>Over the last four and a half years,
<a href="http://www.verasolutions.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Vera Solutions</a> has been designing and building
data systems with Force.com for leading impact-first organizations around the
world. We’ve now worked with 125 clients in more than 40 countries. We’ve
witnessed our partners transform their organizations with good data systems. “É
uma revolução!” said one staffer at PSI Mozambique. We’ve also gained experience
with dozens of other technologies designed to serve social impact organizations.
These tools have enabled our partners to improve their operations in diverse
ways ranging from communicating by SMS with thousands of farmers in Mali, to
collecting loan repayments using MPESA in Kenya, to analyzing household survey
data in India.</p><p>Hundreds of these tools exist, but social impact organizations face three main
barriers to successful implementations:</p><ol><li>Picking the right tool is hard.</li><li>Even if you pick the right tool, a successful implementation of that tool
hinges on solving complex people and process problems.</li><li>No single tool does it all, so you’ve got to figure out how to integrate more
than one — and they rarely ‘play nice’.</li></ol><p>Figuring out the people and the processes, that’s always going to be the hardest
part to get right — whether or not the technical work presents a barrier.
Openfn.org’s first objective is to knock down the technical hurdles so that
organizations can focus on that important contextual stuff.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="/fr/assets/images/techpic-3e8124b4f95b5f6dbf743b755804c8f7.jpg" width="2999" height="1999" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We see a future where the technical setup of a mobile money platform, a
biometrics tool, even an offline clinic registration platform, feels just like
downloading an app from the app store.</p><p>We’re still a long way from that reality, but we’ve built an
<a href="https://www.openfn.org/pricing#open-source" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">open-core</a> integration platform
that’s poised to bring together the “technology for development” landscape with
clicks, not code. Our team of integration specialists and
<a href="http://openfn.org/apps" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apps page</a> guide users to the right tools based on
their needs, our blog will feature in-depth case studies and implementation
guides, and our jobs engine fast-tracks setup of robust integration and
automation solutions, enabling our users to get data flowing from one technology
to another in just a few minutes.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="this-is-where-we-stand">This is where we stand.<a href="#this-is-where-we-stand" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to This is where we stand." title="Direct link to This is where we stand.">​</a></h3><p>Over the last 6 years, OpenFn has delivered interoperability, data integration,
and process automation solutions to dozens of the world’s leading impact-first
organizations, including UNICEF, Population Services International, Population
Council, myAgro, Lwala Community Alliance, Vera Solutions, Dimagi, and more.
OpenFn solutions strengthen existing digital systems, improve service delivery,
save time and money, and help organizations worldwide scale their processes,
programs, and impact. So far, different organizations have integrated more than
X number of technologies, including Open Data Kit (ODK), Kobo Toolbox, DHIS2,
CommCare, Salesforce, custom databases, and more.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>tips</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the new OpenFn Blog]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/05/31/the-new-openfn-blog</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openfn.org/fr/blog/2020/05/31/the-new-openfn-blog</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[For the last few years, several OpenFn contributors and I have been blogging]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the last few years, several OpenFn contributors and I have been blogging
over at Medium. I'm still going to write there from time to time as part of the
<a href="https://www.medium.com/@taylordowns2000" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenFn Founder's Blog</a>, but today, I'm
excited to announce the launch of our own, new, more tightly integrated blog.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="team" src="/fr/assets/images/team-no-td-82059428653414f45e35865b3b8eb0cc.jpg" width="4032" height="3024" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>It will give us more flexibility to tell the stories of our clients journeys to
scale, and all of the contributors to the OpenFn blog can post in the same
place. You can still follow us and receive notifications by subscribing below,
and we hope you'll do so.</p><p>For now, happy integrating!</p><p>— Taylor</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>